nothing gets Americans off quite like
freedom sure are the countries of three
if not America free if you could write
freedom around the world
we're number one we're number oh there
is a freedom ranking and we're ranked
who turns out freedom is constantly
being redefined after 9/11 Americans
were told the trading civil liberties
the security was the new normal and
people all around the world trade away
freedoms every day but could big
trade-offs ever actually be worth it
I've come to Singapore a crazy rich
place with some of the strictest laws on
earth i sat down with journalist Conrad
Raj to learn how the government keeps
its people in line let's talk about some
of the Singapore laws what are some of
the more extreme ones the one that
restrict speech gatherings wrote airs
like many laws in Singapore they are
there to instill some fear you can be
fine for selling gum or forgetting to
flush the toilet but prostitution
they're okay with that gun Rangers sure
it's a carefully designed system of
carrots and sticks the carrots are the
prostitutes the sticks are the actual
sticks they used to cane people oh
there's a guy I mean that they are
signed to do the caning does he have a
nickname is your carry the kind I had no
no and we can give it up to 24 strokes
right yeah yeah and about 26 - yeah
right now in trouble could be but at 72
what the heck yeah I don't have a wife
so there's no other collateral damage
you used to have one she said too much
to be a penalty the government has shown
that it can be reasonable as a former
British colony they decided to emulate
London's speakers corner famous for
drawing big crowds doing
raucous debate so I sent our cameraman
down there to get a shot of this hotbed
of democracy what does his speaker's
corner the hoods without any restriction
you can say whatever you were ah there's
still certain restrictions you don't
have to get a permit or you have to you
still have to get a permit and have to
get a permit and police stations just on
it but you're not being watched by
cameras or anything like that probably
you would be right but apart from the
cameras the police and the permit you're
just ready to do whatever yeah right
good
if Singapore is going to claw back some
of its civil liberties maybe the answer
is the country's young people throughout
history younger generations have taught
social injustice around the world so I
met with a group of college students to
see how they're planning to take on the
man everything I know about Singapore
comes from the movie crazy rich Asians
right that movie is accurate correct
what do you feel about all of
Singapore's rules
I'd say them I say they're quite fair I
feel that the laws necessary for the
country to function I think that the
rules were to allow us to grow to this
point yeah I don't think Singapore has a
lot of opportunities despite the rules
part of the social contract is accepting
that some civil liberties restricted or
suspended okay then it seems that these
young rebels are actually pretty happy
in fact according to a UN survey on
happiness Singapore has climbed the
rankings in recent years to 34 ahead of
more democratic countries like Italy
Spain and Japan
maybe that's because Singaporeans get
three health care and giant tax savings
basically the government is giving away
a bunch of free so no one
complaints but even in Singapore
some things are too important to keep
quiet about have you ever wanted to
speak about something but couldn't
yes multiple times what are those things
like they frown upon stuff that is LGBT
related as a person who comes from the
lgbtq+ community it's very restrictive
here that's right while being gay isn't
technically illegal here Singapore has
come up with a very Singaporean way of
criminalizing it it is illegal to have
gay sex yes but it's not illegal to be
gay yeah I could want to have a but
I just kind of have a cop that's right
is that gay nightclubs there was one
place called Spartacus in Chinatown
Spartacus yeah it Spartacus and then
they come in there and they ride the
place they go you're a gay and then
another person set it up because I'm a
gay no I'm a gay with all this social
injustice is anyone speaking truth to
power now I don't want to brag but
nobody's better at calling out
politicians than comedians same see he's
trying to make it as a stand-up in
Singapore without pissing off the
authorities have you ever been pulled
off stage yes a number of times have had
to learn how to solve dance around the
line how to solve get close enough but
not too close where I get arrested or go
to jail
this people we have conscription and
it's called national service before you
go in remember at first it's about you
becoming each one you like the other is
me
fine as a gay man that it's a difficult
thing here in Singapore it's something
that you trying your best not to think
about right especially since I go on
stage every other night to say hey I'm
gay and I know it's technically illegal
to promote it positively right could you
argue if you got in trouble that you're
playing a character oh yeah but they're
not gonna buy that yeah I've sucked up
too much too many people yeah what would
be enough to go to jail
the closest I've got villages making
government jokes engage yokes at the
same time like if you put it you go this
guy in government is a homosexual would
that be crossing the line yeah because
it's true that's the worst part so there
are people in Singaporean government
that are gay which country doesn't have
gay people in the cabinet a cabinet is a
form of a closet mm-hmm fancy yeah oh my
god yeah he's fella busted me last night
[Laughter]
TV programming does it get censored
before it gets you cleavage get censored
cigarettes get censored alcohol bottles
get censored how do you show you how do
you sent your cigarette geezers
pixilated yes pixelated so to just smoke
in a Japanese penis that's what it looks
like some porn is regulated right oh
yeah they've blocked a little bit stuff
so pornhub is down pornhub I've accessed
pornhub this morning I did I think I can
get porn right now I've never seen
pornhub before my god you're a tree
we'll see if we can get some gay stuff
for you good do they get fisting you
want a gay fisting piece all right this
is what I'm in for
boom Shakalaka Oh what up we got porn 23
year old meth addict extreme fisting
just like you're requested young man
thank you sir
you're very kind right scar can you get
a close-up on that
I don't I've forgotten what the reason
I'm doing this is you know it's easy to
judge Singapore to say that they're all
willing to give up too much I mean free
speech and board but let's not assume
that they're super jealous of us either
would you ever want to live in the u.s.
before maybe no not really - and what
because of Trump yeah I don't feel like
they treat foreigners that well the the
impression of foreigners on them
wouldn't be as good you would be worried
about not feeling welcome there
I think people now don't have the same
perception of the u.s. yes we used to
have ten five years ago right right
right
Americans like to say that the greatest
country in the world because of their
freedom what do you say to that I'd see
there are a lot less freedom dating
there you're not free to go to school
without getting fear of getting shot at
freedom comes at a cost is that just a
cost - you don't want to pay walking on
the street and knowing that the
likelihood of me getting a shot or blown
up is a lot lower than somewhere else in
the West it's a great comfort to me
overall is trading civil liberties for
security a good deal for the
Singaporeans 20 dissipate more
Singaporeans will agree that it's been a
good deal but I think things could have
been liberalized far more than they are
now and without harming security
security is an excuse often to bring out
more restrictive laws right it really is
a false choice freedom or security
that's a message our government needs to
hear - luckily we still have the right
to complain it's a great privilege but
it's only worth something if we use
[Music]
[Applause]